Guide to the Chimpanzee and Human Communication Institute Records 1970-2012 (bulk 1980-2012)
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
- Thesis and Research Tapes, 1984-2010; XX
  - Summer Apprentice Reliability Tapes, 2003; 57
  - M.L. Jensvold talk about language research, 2003; 58
  - Nesting Study, 2003-2004; 59
  - Forage Study, 2003-2005; 60
  - Tennyson Egan Thesis Data, 2005; 61
  - Play Gesture, 2007; 62
  - Holly Bowman Thesis Data, 2003; 63
  - Jensvold Pilot, 2004; 64
  - Jess Hartel Thesis Data, 2005; 65
  - Susan Shiau Thesis, 2005; 66
  - “WH” Questions, 2005; 67
  - Jackie Smith Thesis Data, 2005; 68
  - Locomotion Study, 2006; 69
  - Animal Welfare Institute, M.L. Jensvold, Caregiver Behavior Study, 2006; 70
  - Gina Stadtner Thesis Data, 2008-2009; 71
  - Dani Bismanovsky Thesis Data, 2010; 72
  - Object location/pointing Thesis Data, 73
  - Forage Tapes, 74
- Adventitious Tapes, 1985-Present; XXI
  Adventitious refers to a series of recordings that are not a part of a structured research project. The series includes recordings of holiday celebrations, closed circuit meals for Advanced Chimposiums, new enclosures or structures, or activities developed to provide enrichment for the chimpanzees. The tapes in this series are on Betamax, VHS, and mini Digital Videocassettes.
- Video Follow Data, 1985-2011; XXII
  The video follow data provides information regarding the order of filming each chimpanzee, any notable interactions or events, and any interruptions or changes in the filming schedule. The charts are stored in 3-ring binders.
- ChimpanZoo, 1985-1994; XXIII
  The ChimpanZoo Research, Education, and Enrichment Program is sponsored by the Jane Goodall Institute. Records are housed in 3-ring binders.
- Tech Shift Reports, 1986-Present; XXIV
  Shift reports are records of the daily routine in caring for the chimpanzees. From 1986-1993 the reports contained additional information regarding interesting interactions or new signs which is now reserved for sign logs. Current shift reports focus on the shifting of chimps, unlocking of enclosures, when meals are served, and anything outside of “normal” activity occurs. The reports are stored in 3-ring binders.
- Training Manuals, 1987-1992; XXV
  Old training manuals and taxonomies for caretakers from the period of time the chimpanzees were housed in the Psychology building. The manuals are housed in 3-ring binders.
- Enrichment Logs, 1988-2005; XXVI
  Enrichment logs are checklists of common enrichment categories the chimpanzees are offered each day. Caregivers note which categories of enrichment are offered to the chimpanzees on a particular day as well as any enhanced enrichment that does not fall into one of the common categories. The logs are stored in 3-ring binders.
- Chimpmoove, 1991-1993; XXVII
  Data collected prior to and immediately after the move of the chimpanzees from the Psychology Building to the Chimpanzee and Human Communication Institute.
- Sign of the Day, 1992-2004; XXVIII
  The Sign of the Day Project prompted the chimpanzees to sign about a target sign that changed daily. The records are housed in 3-ring binders.
- Fieldwork, 1992-2005; XXIX
  Fieldwork research has been conducted off-site by researchers from the Chimpanzee and Human Communication Institute at both African field sites and African sanctuaries. The Cameroon Wildlife Aid Fund is now known as: Ape Action Africa. Gombe (Tanzania), Africa and Kibale (Uganda), Africa tapes are on VHS and Cameroon and Zambia tapes are on mini Digital Videocassettes.
  - Gombe, Tanzania, Africa, 1992-1996; 1
  - Kibale, Uganda, Africa, 1996-1998; 2
  - Chimfunshi Wildlife Orphanage, Zambia, Africa, 2005; 3
  - Cameroon Wildlife Aid Fund, Cameroon, Africa, 2005; 4
  - Sanaga-Yong Chimpanzee Rescue Center, Cameroon, Africa, 2005; 5
- Elderhostel, 1994-1995; XXX
- Field Logs, 1994-Present; XXXI
  Handwritten, observational notes recorded from Berm observational area. Logs are stored in 3-ring binders in the computer room.
- Summer Apprentice Program, 1995-Present; XXXII
  The Summer Apprentice Program runs for an eight week session each summer and provides an opportunity for up to fifteen students or faculty to perform and participate in research. This series includes resulting research as well as administrative records (i.e. applications, evaluations, handbooks).
- Activity Budgets, 1996-1999; XXXIII
  Activity Budgets examine the how the chimpanzees spend their days and the activities they engage in.
- Proximity Data/Post-Conflict Interaction Study, 1997-2001; XXXIV
  Data is stored in 3-ring binders housed in the conference room.
- Conversational Video Follow Tapes, 2002-Present; XXXV
  Conversational Video Follow tapes are recorded interactions between chimpanzees and human caregivers. Conversational Video Follow is not as structured as regular video follow and does not have time restrictions or adhere to a formal schedule.
- Slides and Photographs, 1966-2004; XXXVI
  The photographs and slides focus on capturing chimpanzee signing, interaction between the chimpanzees, and interactions between chimpanzees and humans. Other emphases of the series include: the building stages of the Chimpanzee and Human Communication Institute; Jane Goodall’s visits to Central Washington University; and photographs of the chimpanzees as infants. Negatives for the photographs are also contained within this series.